{"id":"99905969-9ffb-48cd-a848-c55771d89599","question":"The genial tubercles are best visualized on which type of radiograph?","options":["Panoramic","Periapical","Occlusal","Bitewing"],"answer":"Occlusal","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"a0575ee3-92bb-4ccf-b7a2-1aa0c6134705","question":"Which of the following is critical to the cementation process of a porcelain veneer?","options":["Etching the interior surface of the veneer with maleic acid.","Placement of a coat of primer","Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","Placement of silane on unetched surfaces"],"answer":"Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"b0290308-131e-4339-b68c-105cb1078f02","question":"For a mandibular denture impression, the muscle determining the form of the lingual flange in the molar region is","options":["lateral pterygoid","genioglossus","geniohyoid","mylohyoid","medial pterygoid"],"answer":"mylohyoid","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"7c96d7c6-261e-4e7b-854c-a9a0d694abd0","question":"A patient wearing complete dentures complains of tingling and numbness in the lower lip bilaterally. This is often an indication of","options":["defective occlusal contacts","neoplastic invasion of the inferior mandibular nerve.","allergy to denture base material","impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","impingement of denture on mandibular nerve"],"answer":"impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"11e47d24-f8d0-4b9e-935e-a050fb7b212d","question":"In children and adolescents, the long term effects of rapid palatal expansion (0.5mm/day) compared to slow palatal expansion (0.5mm/week) are","options":["less skeletal expansion and more dental expansion","Causes opening of the sphenooccipital suture","more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","less stable"],"answer":"more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"70e83fba-c7c7-40d6-a2a4-56e2a977ad4a","question":"Aggressive periodontitis has all of the following features EXCEPT","options":["radiographic evidence of bone loss","rapid attachment loss","ulcerations of the gingiva","suspected periodontal microbial pathogens"],"answer":"ulcerations of the gingiva","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"afce7a60-c548-47a1-84ea-88a9a5d0be60","question":"The earliest clinical sign of gingivitis is","options":["change in consistency of the attached gingiva","increased tooth mobility","bleeding on probing.","change in color of the attached gingiva"],"answer":"bleeding on probing.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"151e06ef-630b-4b2e-bbc5-067b2e23ad24","question":"In chronic periodontitis, the sulcular epithelium has the following characteristics EXCEPT","options":["may be ulcerated","is a barrier to bacterial invasion","undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","is permeable to bacterial enzymes and toxins"],"answer":"undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"f9f18526-42d4-4e97-9b67-87780ee02fde","question":"Guided tissue regeneration surgery selectively promotes the growth of all of the following EXCEPT","options":["cementoblasts.","endothelial cells","epithelial cells","osteoblasts"],"answer":"epithelial cells","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"dd410c41-0c5d-478b-9f15-6a46bf16315b","question":"A 5 year old child is diagnosed with leukocyte adherence deficiency and is also affected with generalized severe bone loss adjacent to his primary teeth. What is the diagnosis?","options":["Gingival diseases modified by systemic factors","Generalized aggressive periodontitis","Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","Generalized chronic periodontitis"],"answer":"Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"e50b535f-110a-46b6-886d-49534a089aeb","question":"Tetracycline","options":["can be given in conjunction with penicillin","is bactericidal","interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","disrupts the bacterial cell wall"],"answer":"interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"c89514d0-3876-4de0-b85a-902344a491b3","question":"During the fabrication of a removable complete denture, block out and relief is placed on the","options":["remount cast","master cast","diagnostic cast","refractory cast"],"answer":"diagnostic cast","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"05636a60-b2cb-4ea9-a262-05ae1c99cbe0","question":"The advantage of a posterior composite resin restoration when compared to amalgam is an immediate reduction in","options":["caries risk for patients with poor oral hygiene","marginal leakage","post-operative sensitivity.","technique sensitivity"],"answer":"post-operative sensitivity.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"64010f88-4129-4b28-a1d2-6dbb6c1b1727","question":"When a simple tipping force is applied to the crown of a single-rooted tooth, the centre of rotation is located","options":["within the cervical one third of the root.","at the apex","within the apical half of the root","at the cervical line"],"answer":"within the apical half of the root","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ff543827-6994-4bb7-961a-2bbc1e835f62","question":"The principal use of the rubber dam during placement of a composite resin restoration is to provide","options":["access to the operating field","interproximal gingival retraction","protection from fluid contamination.","contrast between the tooth and the operating field"],"answer":"protection from fluid contamination.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"d2ae1d59-6159-4934-a951-3986bd2fa810","question":"High telomerase activity is associated with","options":["cystic fibrosis","diabetes mellitus","malignant tumors","hyperthyroidism"],"answer":"malignant tumors","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ab2e7db1-f114-42d6-b686-e09113d3c795","question":"The dentino-enamel junction is the most sensitive portion of a tooth because","options":["odontoblastic tubules help convey hydrostatic forces to the pulp cells","free nerve endings terminate on odontoblasts at this region","odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","ameloblasts make synaptic connections with odontoblasts at this junction."],"answer":"odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"cf9fbdd6-323c-4530-bdf9-53a647e80f39","question":"Healthy attached gingiva","options":["has no rete pegs","has no basal cell layer","is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","contains elastic fibers"],"answer":"is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"99905969-9ffb-48cd-a848-c55771d89599","question":"The genial tubercles are best visualized on which type of radiograph?","options":["Panoramic","Periapical","Occlusal","Bitewing"],"answer":"Occlusal","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"a0575ee3-92bb-4ccf-b7a2-1aa0c6134705","question":"Which of the following is critical to the cementation process of a porcelain veneer?","options":["Etching the interior surface of the veneer with maleic acid.","Placement of a coat of primer","Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","Placement of silane on unetched surfaces"],"answer":"Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"b0290308-131e-4339-b68c-105cb1078f02","question":"For a mandibular denture impression, the muscle determining the form of the lingual flange in the molar region is","options":["lateral pterygoid","genioglossus","geniohyoid","mylohyoid","medial pterygoid"],"answer":"mylohyoid","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"7c96d7c6-261e-4e7b-854c-a9a0d694abd0","question":"A patient wearing complete dentures complains of tingling and numbness in the lower lip bilaterally. This is often an indication of","options":["defective occlusal contacts","neoplastic invasion of the inferior mandibular nerve.","allergy to denture base material","impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","impingement of denture on mandibular nerve"],"answer":"impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"11e47d24-f8d0-4b9e-935e-a050fb7b212d","question":"In children and adolescents, the long term effects of rapid palatal expansion (0.5mm/day) compared to slow palatal expansion (0.5mm/week) are","options":["less skeletal expansion and more dental expansion","Causes opening of the sphenooccipital suture","more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","less stable"],"answer":"more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"70e83fba-c7c7-40d6-a2a4-56e2a977ad4a","question":"Aggressive periodontitis has all of the following features EXCEPT","options":["radiographic evidence of bone loss","rapid attachment loss","ulcerations of the gingiva","suspected periodontal microbial pathogens"],"answer":"ulcerations of the gingiva","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"afce7a60-c548-47a1-84ea-88a9a5d0be60","question":"The earliest clinical sign of gingivitis is","options":["change in consistency of the attached gingiva","increased tooth mobility","bleeding on probing.","change in color of the attached gingiva"],"answer":"bleeding on probing.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"151e06ef-630b-4b2e-bbc5-067b2e23ad24","question":"In chronic periodontitis, the sulcular epithelium has the following characteristics EXCEPT","options":["may be ulcerated","is a barrier to bacterial invasion","undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","is permeable to bacterial enzymes and toxins"],"answer":"undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"f9f18526-42d4-4e97-9b67-87780ee02fde","question":"Guided tissue regeneration surgery selectively promotes the growth of all of the following EXCEPT","options":["cementoblasts.","endothelial cells","epithelial cells","osteoblasts"],"answer":"epithelial cells","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"dd410c41-0c5d-478b-9f15-6a46bf16315b","question":"A 5 year old child is diagnosed with leukocyte adherence deficiency and is also affected with generalized severe bone loss adjacent to his primary teeth. What is the diagnosis?","options":["Gingival diseases modified by systemic factors","Generalized aggressive periodontitis","Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","Generalized chronic periodontitis"],"answer":"Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"e50b535f-110a-46b6-886d-49534a089aeb","question":"Tetracycline","options":["can be given in conjunction with penicillin","is bactericidal","interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","disrupts the bacterial cell wall"],"answer":"interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"c89514d0-3876-4de0-b85a-902344a491b3","question":"During the fabrication of a removable complete denture, block out and relief is placed on the","options":["remount cast","master cast","diagnostic cast","refractory cast"],"answer":"diagnostic cast","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"05636a60-b2cb-4ea9-a262-05ae1c99cbe0","question":"The advantage of a posterior composite resin restoration when compared to amalgam is an immediate reduction in","options":["caries risk for patients with poor oral hygiene","marginal leakage","post-operative sensitivity.","technique sensitivity"],"answer":"post-operative sensitivity.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"64010f88-4129-4b28-a1d2-6dbb6c1b1727","question":"When a simple tipping force is applied to the crown of a single-rooted tooth, the centre of rotation is located","options":["within the cervical one third of the root.","at the apex","within the apical half of the root","at the cervical line"],"answer":"within the apical half of the root","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ff543827-6994-4bb7-961a-2bbc1e835f62","question":"The principal use of the rubber dam during placement of a composite resin restoration is to provide","options":["access to the operating field","interproximal gingival retraction","protection from fluid contamination.","contrast between the tooth and the operating field"],"answer":"protection from fluid contamination.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"d2ae1d59-6159-4934-a951-3986bd2fa810","question":"High telomerase activity is associated with","options":["cystic fibrosis","diabetes mellitus","malignant tumors","hyperthyroidism"],"answer":"malignant tumors","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ab2e7db1-f114-42d6-b686-e09113d3c795","question":"The dentino-enamel junction is the most sensitive portion of a tooth because","options":["odontoblastic tubules help convey hydrostatic forces to the pulp cells","free nerve endings terminate on odontoblasts at this region","odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","ameloblasts make synaptic connections with odontoblasts at this junction."],"answer":"odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"cf9fbdd6-323c-4530-bdf9-53a647e80f39","question":"Healthy attached gingiva","options":["has no rete pegs","has no basal cell layer","is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","contains elastic fibers"],"answer":"is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"99905969-9ffb-48cd-a848-c55771d89599","question":"The genial tubercles are best visualized on which type of radiograph?","options":["Panoramic","Periapical","Occlusal","Bitewing"],"answer":"Occlusal","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"a0575ee3-92bb-4ccf-b7a2-1aa0c6134705","question":"Which of the following is critical to the cementation process of a porcelain veneer?","options":["Etching the interior surface of the veneer with maleic acid.","Placement of a coat of primer","Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","Placement of silane on unetched surfaces"],"answer":"Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"b0290308-131e-4339-b68c-105cb1078f02","question":"For a mandibular denture impression, the muscle determining the form of the lingual flange in the molar region is","options":["lateral pterygoid","genioglossus","geniohyoid","mylohyoid","medial pterygoid"],"answer":"mylohyoid","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"7c96d7c6-261e-4e7b-854c-a9a0d694abd0","question":"A patient wearing complete dentures complains of tingling and numbness in the lower lip bilaterally. This is often an indication of","options":["defective occlusal contacts","neoplastic invasion of the inferior mandibular nerve.","allergy to denture base material","impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","impingement of denture on mandibular nerve"],"answer":"impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"11e47d24-f8d0-4b9e-935e-a050fb7b212d","question":"In children and adolescents, the long term effects of rapid palatal expansion (0.5mm/day) compared to slow palatal expansion (0.5mm/week) are","options":["less skeletal expansion and more dental expansion","Causes opening of the sphenooccipital suture","more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","less stable"],"answer":"more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"70e83fba-c7c7-40d6-a2a4-56e2a977ad4a","question":"Aggressive periodontitis has all of the following features EXCEPT","options":["radiographic evidence of bone loss","rapid attachment loss","ulcerations of the gingiva","suspected periodontal microbial pathogens"],"answer":"ulcerations of the gingiva","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"afce7a60-c548-47a1-84ea-88a9a5d0be60","question":"The earliest clinical sign of gingivitis is","options":["change in consistency of the attached gingiva","increased tooth mobility","bleeding on probing.","change in color of the attached gingiva"],"answer":"bleeding on probing.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"151e06ef-630b-4b2e-bbc5-067b2e23ad24","question":"In chronic periodontitis, the sulcular epithelium has the following characteristics EXCEPT","options":["may be ulcerated","is a barrier to bacterial invasion","undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","is permeable to bacterial enzymes and toxins"],"answer":"undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"f9f18526-42d4-4e97-9b67-87780ee02fde","question":"Guided tissue regeneration surgery selectively promotes the growth of all of the following EXCEPT","options":["cementoblasts.","endothelial cells","epithelial cells","osteoblasts"],"answer":"epithelial cells","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"dd410c41-0c5d-478b-9f15-6a46bf16315b","question":"A 5 year old child is diagnosed with leukocyte adherence deficiency and is also affected with generalized severe bone loss adjacent to his primary teeth. What is the diagnosis?","options":["Gingival diseases modified by systemic factors","Generalized aggressive periodontitis","Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","Generalized chronic periodontitis"],"answer":"Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"e50b535f-110a-46b6-886d-49534a089aeb","question":"Tetracycline","options":["can be given in conjunction with penicillin","is bactericidal","interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","disrupts the bacterial cell wall"],"answer":"interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"c89514d0-3876-4de0-b85a-902344a491b3","question":"During the fabrication of a removable complete denture, block out and relief is placed on the","options":["remount cast","master cast","diagnostic cast","refractory cast"],"answer":"diagnostic cast","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"05636a60-b2cb-4ea9-a262-05ae1c99cbe0","question":"The advantage of a posterior composite resin restoration when compared to amalgam is an immediate reduction in","options":["caries risk for patients with poor oral hygiene","marginal leakage","post-operative sensitivity.","technique sensitivity"],"answer":"post-operative sensitivity.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"64010f88-4129-4b28-a1d2-6dbb6c1b1727","question":"When a simple tipping force is applied to the crown of a single-rooted tooth, the centre of rotation is located","options":["within the cervical one third of the root.","at the apex","within the apical half of the root","at the cervical line"],"answer":"within the apical half of the root","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ff543827-6994-4bb7-961a-2bbc1e835f62","question":"The principal use of the rubber dam during placement of a composite resin restoration is to provide","options":["access to the operating field","interproximal gingival retraction","protection from fluid contamination.","contrast between the tooth and the operating field"],"answer":"protection from fluid contamination.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"d2ae1d59-6159-4934-a951-3986bd2fa810","question":"High telomerase activity is associated with","options":["cystic fibrosis","diabetes mellitus","malignant tumors","hyperthyroidism"],"answer":"malignant tumors","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ab2e7db1-f114-42d6-b686-e09113d3c795","question":"The dentino-enamel junction is the most sensitive portion of a tooth because","options":["odontoblastic tubules help convey hydrostatic forces to the pulp cells","free nerve endings terminate on odontoblasts at this region","odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","ameloblasts make synaptic connections with odontoblasts at this junction."],"answer":"odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"cf9fbdd6-323c-4530-bdf9-53a647e80f39","question":"Healthy attached gingiva","options":["has no rete pegs","has no basal cell layer","is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","contains elastic fibers"],"answer":"is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"99905969-9ffb-48cd-a848-c55771d89599","question":"The genial tubercles are best visualized on which type of radiograph?","options":["Panoramic","Periapical","Occlusal","Bitewing"],"answer":"Occlusal","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"a0575ee3-92bb-4ccf-b7a2-1aa0c6134705","question":"Which of the following is critical to the cementation process of a porcelain veneer?","options":["Etching the interior surface of the veneer with maleic acid.","Placement of a coat of primer","Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","Placement of silane on unetched surfaces"],"answer":"Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"b0290308-131e-4339-b68c-105cb1078f02","question":"For a mandibular denture impression, the muscle determining the form of the lingual flange in the molar region is","options":["lateral pterygoid","genioglossus","geniohyoid","mylohyoid","medial pterygoid"],"answer":"mylohyoid","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"7c96d7c6-261e-4e7b-854c-a9a0d694abd0","question":"A patient wearing complete dentures complains of tingling and numbness in the lower lip bilaterally. This is often an indication of","options":["defective occlusal contacts","neoplastic invasion of the inferior mandibular nerve.","allergy to denture base material","impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","impingement of denture on mandibular nerve"],"answer":"impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"11e47d24-f8d0-4b9e-935e-a050fb7b212d","question":"In children and adolescents, the long term effects of rapid palatal expansion (0.5mm/day) compared to slow palatal expansion (0.5mm/week) are","options":["less skeletal expansion and more dental expansion","Causes opening of the sphenooccipital suture","more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","less stable"],"answer":"more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"70e83fba-c7c7-40d6-a2a4-56e2a977ad4a","question":"Aggressive periodontitis has all of the following features EXCEPT","options":["radiographic evidence of bone loss","rapid attachment loss","ulcerations of the gingiva","suspected periodontal microbial pathogens"],"answer":"ulcerations of the gingiva","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"afce7a60-c548-47a1-84ea-88a9a5d0be60","question":"The earliest clinical sign of gingivitis is","options":["change in consistency of the attached gingiva","increased tooth mobility","bleeding on probing.","change in color of the attached gingiva"],"answer":"bleeding on probing.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"151e06ef-630b-4b2e-bbc5-067b2e23ad24","question":"In chronic periodontitis, the sulcular epithelium has the following characteristics EXCEPT","options":["may be ulcerated","is a barrier to bacterial invasion","undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","is permeable to bacterial enzymes and toxins"],"answer":"undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"f9f18526-42d4-4e97-9b67-87780ee02fde","question":"Guided tissue regeneration surgery selectively promotes the growth of all of the following EXCEPT","options":["cementoblasts.","endothelial cells","epithelial cells","osteoblasts"],"answer":"epithelial cells","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"dd410c41-0c5d-478b-9f15-6a46bf16315b","question":"A 5 year old child is diagnosed with leukocyte adherence deficiency and is also affected with generalized severe bone loss adjacent to his primary teeth. What is the diagnosis?","options":["Gingival diseases modified by systemic factors","Generalized aggressive periodontitis","Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","Generalized chronic periodontitis"],"answer":"Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"e50b535f-110a-46b6-886d-49534a089aeb","question":"Tetracycline","options":["can be given in conjunction with penicillin","is bactericidal","interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","disrupts the bacterial cell wall"],"answer":"interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"c89514d0-3876-4de0-b85a-902344a491b3","question":"During the fabrication of a removable complete denture, block out and relief is placed on the","options":["remount cast","master cast","diagnostic cast","refractory cast"],"answer":"diagnostic cast","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"05636a60-b2cb-4ea9-a262-05ae1c99cbe0","question":"The advantage of a posterior composite resin restoration when compared to amalgam is an immediate reduction in","options":["caries risk for patients with poor oral hygiene","marginal leakage","post-operative sensitivity.","technique sensitivity"],"answer":"post-operative sensitivity.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"64010f88-4129-4b28-a1d2-6dbb6c1b1727","question":"When a simple tipping force is applied to the crown of a single-rooted tooth, the centre of rotation is located","options":["within the cervical one third of the root.","at the apex","within the apical half of the root","at the cervical line"],"answer":"within the apical half of the root","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ff543827-6994-4bb7-961a-2bbc1e835f62","question":"The principal use of the rubber dam during placement of a composite resin restoration is to provide","options":["access to the operating field","interproximal gingival retraction","protection from fluid contamination.","contrast between the tooth and the operating field"],"answer":"protection from fluid contamination.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"d2ae1d59-6159-4934-a951-3986bd2fa810","question":"High telomerase activity is associated with","options":["cystic fibrosis","diabetes mellitus","malignant tumors","hyperthyroidism"],"answer":"malignant tumors","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ab2e7db1-f114-42d6-b686-e09113d3c795","question":"The dentino-enamel junction is the most sensitive portion of a tooth because","options":["odontoblastic tubules help convey hydrostatic forces to the pulp cells","free nerve endings terminate on odontoblasts at this region","odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","ameloblasts make synaptic connections with odontoblasts at this junction."],"answer":"odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"cf9fbdd6-323c-4530-bdf9-53a647e80f39","question":"Healthy attached gingiva","options":["has no rete pegs","has no basal cell layer","is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","contains elastic fibers"],"answer":"is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"7c96d7c6-261e-4e7b-854c-a9a0d694abd0","question":"A patient wearing complete dentures complains of tingling and numbness in the lower lip bilaterally. This is often an indication of","options":["defective occlusal contacts","neoplastic invasion of the inferior mandibular nerve.","allergy to denture base material","impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","impingement of denture on mandibular nerve"],"answer":"impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"11e47d24-f8d0-4b9e-935e-a050fb7b212d","question":"In children and adolescents, the long term effects of rapid palatal expansion (0.5mm/day) compared to slow palatal expansion (0.5mm/week) are","options":["less skeletal expansion and more dental expansion","Causes opening of the sphenooccipital suture","more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","less stable"],"answer":"more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"70e83fba-c7c7-40d6-a2a4-56e2a977ad4a","question":"Aggressive periodontitis has all of the following features EXCEPT","options":["radiographic evidence of bone loss","rapid attachment loss","ulcerations of the gingiva","suspected periodontal microbial pathogens"],"answer":"ulcerations of the gingiva","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"afce7a60-c548-47a1-84ea-88a9a5d0be60","question":"The earliest clinical sign of gingivitis is","options":["change in consistency of the attached gingiva","increased tooth mobility","bleeding on probing.","change in color of the attached gingiva"],"answer":"bleeding on probing.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"151e06ef-630b-4b2e-bbc5-067b2e23ad24","question":"In chronic periodontitis, the sulcular epithelium has the following characteristics EXCEPT","options":["may be ulcerated","is a barrier to bacterial invasion","undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","is permeable to bacterial enzymes and toxins"],"answer":"undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"f9f18526-42d4-4e97-9b67-87780ee02fde","question":"Guided tissue regeneration surgery selectively promotes the growth of all of the following EXCEPT","options":["cementoblasts.","endothelial cells","epithelial cells","osteoblasts"],"answer":"epithelial cells","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"dd410c41-0c5d-478b-9f15-6a46bf16315b","question":"A 5 year old child is diagnosed with leukocyte adherence deficiency and is also affected with generalized severe bone loss adjacent to his primary teeth. What is the diagnosis?","options":["Gingival diseases modified by systemic factors","Generalized aggressive periodontitis","Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","Generalized chronic periodontitis"],"answer":"Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"e50b535f-110a-46b6-886d-49534a089aeb","question":"Tetracycline","options":["can be given in conjunction with penicillin","is bactericidal","interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","disrupts the bacterial cell wall"],"answer":"interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"c89514d0-3876-4de0-b85a-902344a491b3","question":"During the fabrication of a removable complete denture, block out and relief is placed on the","options":["remount cast","master cast","diagnostic cast","refractory cast"],"answer":"diagnostic cast","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"05636a60-b2cb-4ea9-a262-05ae1c99cbe0","question":"The advantage of a posterior composite resin restoration when compared to amalgam is an immediate reduction in","options":["caries risk for patients with poor oral hygiene","marginal leakage","post-operative sensitivity.","technique sensitivity"],"answer":"post-operative sensitivity.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"64010f88-4129-4b28-a1d2-6dbb6c1b1727","question":"When a simple tipping force is applied to the crown of a single-rooted tooth, the centre of rotation is located","options":["within the cervical one third of the root.","at the apex","within the apical half of the root","at the cervical line"],"answer":"within the apical half of the root","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ff543827-6994-4bb7-961a-2bbc1e835f62","question":"The principal use of the rubber dam during placement of a composite resin restoration is to provide","options":["access to the operating field","interproximal gingival retraction","protection from fluid contamination.","contrast between the tooth and the operating field"],"answer":"protection from fluid contamination.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"d2ae1d59-6159-4934-a951-3986bd2fa810","question":"High telomerase activity is associated with","options":["cystic fibrosis","diabetes mellitus","malignant tumors","hyperthyroidism"],"answer":"malignant tumors","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"ab2e7db1-f114-42d6-b686-e09113d3c795","question":"The dentino-enamel junction is the most sensitive portion of a tooth because","options":["odontoblastic tubules help convey hydrostatic forces to the pulp cells","free nerve endings terminate on odontoblasts at this region","odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","ameloblasts make synaptic connections with odontoblasts at this junction."],"answer":"odontoblastic processes branch considerably at this region.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"cf9fbdd6-323c-4530-bdf9-53a647e80f39","question":"Healthy attached gingiva","options":["has no rete pegs","has no basal cell layer","is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","contains elastic fibers"],"answer":"is closely bound to underlying periosteum.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"99905969-9ffb-48cd-a848-c55771d89599","question":"The genial tubercles are best visualized on which type of radiograph?","options":["Panoramic","Periapical","Occlusal","Bitewing"],"answer":"Occlusal","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"a0575ee3-92bb-4ccf-b7a2-1aa0c6134705","question":"Which of the following is critical to the cementation process of a porcelain veneer?","options":["Etching the interior surface of the veneer with maleic acid.","Placement of a coat of primer","Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","Placement of silane on unetched surfaces"],"answer":"Etching the interior surface of the veneer with hydrofluoric acid.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"b0290308-131e-4339-b68c-105cb1078f02","question":"For a mandibular denture impression, the muscle determining the form of the lingual flange in the molar region is","options":["lateral pterygoid","genioglossus","geniohyoid","mylohyoid","medial pterygoid"],"answer":"mylohyoid","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"7c96d7c6-261e-4e7b-854c-a9a0d694abd0","question":"A patient wearing complete dentures complains of tingling and numbness in the lower lip bilaterally. This is often an indication of","options":["defective occlusal contacts","neoplastic invasion of the inferior mandibular nerve.","allergy to denture base material","impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","impingement of denture on mandibular nerve"],"answer":"impingement of denture upon mental nerve.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"11e47d24-f8d0-4b9e-935e-a050fb7b212d","question":"In children and adolescents, the long term effects of rapid palatal expansion (0.5mm/day) compared to slow palatal expansion (0.5mm/week) are","options":["less skeletal expansion and more dental expansion","Causes opening of the sphenooccipital suture","more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","less stable"],"answer":"more skeletal expansion and less dental expansion","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"70e83fba-c7c7-40d6-a2a4-56e2a977ad4a","question":"Aggressive periodontitis has all of the following features EXCEPT","options":["radiographic evidence of bone loss","rapid attachment loss","ulcerations of the gingiva","suspected periodontal microbial pathogens"],"answer":"ulcerations of the gingiva","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"afce7a60-c548-47a1-84ea-88a9a5d0be60","question":"The earliest clinical sign of gingivitis is","options":["change in consistency of the attached gingiva","increased tooth mobility","bleeding on probing.","change in color of the attached gingiva"],"answer":"bleeding on probing.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"151e06ef-630b-4b2e-bbc5-067b2e23ad24","question":"In chronic periodontitis, the sulcular epithelium has the following characteristics EXCEPT","options":["may be ulcerated","is a barrier to bacterial invasion","undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","is permeable to bacterial enzymes and toxins"],"answer":"undergoes both degenerative and proliferative changes","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"f9f18526-42d4-4e97-9b67-87780ee02fde","question":"Guided tissue regeneration surgery selectively promotes the growth of all of the following EXCEPT","options":["cementoblasts.","endothelial cells","epithelial cells","osteoblasts"],"answer":"epithelial cells","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"dd410c41-0c5d-478b-9f15-6a46bf16315b","question":"A 5 year old child is diagnosed with leukocyte adherence deficiency and is also affected with generalized severe bone loss adjacent to his primary teeth. What is the diagnosis?","options":["Gingival diseases modified by systemic factors","Generalized aggressive periodontitis","Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","Generalized chronic periodontitis"],"answer":"Periodontitis as a manifestation of systemic disease.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"e50b535f-110a-46b6-886d-49534a089aeb","question":"Tetracycline","options":["can be given in conjunction with penicillin","is bactericidal","interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","disrupts the bacterial cell wall"],"answer":"interferes with bacterial protein synthesis.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"c89514d0-3876-4de0-b85a-902344a491b3","question":"During the fabrication of a removable complete denture, block out and relief is placed on the","options":["remount cast","master cast","diagnostic cast","refractory cast"],"answer":"diagnostic cast","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}
{"id":"05636a60-b2cb-4ea9-a262-05ae1c99cbe0","question":"The advantage of a posterior composite resin restoration when compared to amalgam is an immediate reduction in","options":["caries risk for patients with poor oral hygiene","marginal leakage","post-operative sensitivity.","technique sensitivity"],"answer":"post-operative sensitivity.","visited":false,"batch":"testBatch","correctAttempts":0,"failedAttempts":0}